<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Punk Domains Blog</title><link>https://blog.punk.domains/</link><description>Recent content on Punk Domains Blog</description><image><url>https://blog.punk.domains/cover.jpg</url><link>https://blog.punk.domains/cover.jpg</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 18:32:22 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.punk.domains/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why every DAO/community needs their own domain?</title><link>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/why-every-dao-needs-own-domain/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 18:32:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/why-every-dao-needs-own-domain/</guid><description>Every crypto/NFT community starts with an idea. First it grows to a few fans. A few supporters. Few contributors. And it keeps growing and growing. Then it sets up a Discord or Telegram group. Then it becomes a thing. A brand.
Some of you take it a step further and form a DAO with its own token. But the basic principle stays the same. You are a group of people who share the same passion and vision.</description></item><item><title>How to set a profile picture for your punk domain?</title><link>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/how-to-set-pfp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 11:32:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/how-to-set-pfp/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s assume you already have your own punk domain. If you still haven’t got one, here is a step-by-step guide to get yours. Seriously, you should get one. 😎
Having your own digital identity in web3 is a powerful tool. There are so many things that you can do with it. In this guide we&amp;rsquo;ll tell you how to set a profile picture for your punk domain.
For every domain that you own, you can set arbitrary custom data.</description></item><item><title>On the path to becoming the most influential DAO in the L2 space - Interview with Exo from Layer2DAO</title><link>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/layer2dao-exo-interview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 08:32:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/layer2dao-exo-interview/</guid><description>Layer2DAO is the first DAO ever to get a top-level domain via the Punk Domains protocol (the .L2 domain).
We’ve reached out to Layer2DAO founder Exosphere and asked him a few questions.
Explain to me like I am 10 years old. 🙂 What is Layer2DAO? Layer2DAO is a group of Ethereum and web3 enthusiasts that want to help expand the Ethereum L2 ecosystem.
We formed the DAO to use its treasury to invest into high-impact L2 protocols and ecosystem plays, serving as a diversified venture fund for investors looking to gain exposure to the L2 ecosystem growth.</description></item><item><title>How to buy your first punk domain?</title><link>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/how-to-buy-first-domain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 08:32:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/how-to-buy-first-domain/</guid><description>You have just found the second most amazing thing on the internet - besides cute cat videos, that is. 😸
Meet Punk Domains, a magical place where you can create your own digital identity for the Web3. Fully decentralized and permissionless on the blockchain. The way it should be.
To get your first Punk Domain you need:
Metamask (or a similar web3 wallet: Rabby, Tally, etc.) Idea for a name (this is a tough one, I know 😅) Choose your network (Optimism, BNB, Gnosis, Polygon, Arbitrum) Choose your favorite TLD (.</description></item><item><title>Punk Domains protocol is modular. Let's see how it works!</title><link>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/modular/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 14:42:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/modular/</guid><description>Punk Domains protocol was built with modularity in mind, which makes it very flexible and allows for different parts of the module to be owned by different owners (for example, TLDs or even factories can be owned by a different owners).
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the graphical representation of the protocol and then dive into different parts.
TLD factories We&amp;rsquo;ll start with the main component of the Punk Domains architecture: a TLD factory.</description></item><item><title>100% on-chain. It's important.</title><link>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/onchain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 09:33:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/onchain/</guid><description>A very important feature of Punk Domains is that it&amp;rsquo;s a 100% on-chain protocol.
But what does that mean?
On-chain domain name The information about which address owns (or resolves to) a domain name is written on the blockchain.
This seems to go without saying for web3 projects, but there are some projects that present themselves as blockchain domain name services, but in fact store the mapping between a domain name and an address on a centralized server.</description></item><item><title>Migrating from v1 to v2</title><link>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/v2-migration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 10:33:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/v2-migration/</guid><description>On 23 March 2022, Punk Domains has migrated to version 2. If you&amp;rsquo;ve minted domains in V1, you&amp;rsquo;ll automatically get new ones. Old ones will be marked as deprecated, so just ignore them. All newly created domains are now v2 domains.
We have added new exciting features to Punk Domains and making it more gas efficient. 🤘
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at what&amp;rsquo;s new!
1. New default domain image The most visible change is a new default domain image.</description></item><item><title>Domains for DAOs and communities</title><link>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/domains-for-daos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 08:32:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/domains-for-daos/</guid><description>Every top-level domain (like .web3, .spartan, .klima) within the Punk Domains protocol can be owned by a different entity. Which makes it perfect for DAOs and communities.
But what are the benefits of owning a domain if you&amp;rsquo;re a DAO?
1. Unity and belonging Let&amp;rsquo;s say there&amp;rsquo;s a DAO called BestDAO with very active and excited community members. BestDAO decides to create a top-level domain (TLD) on Punk Domains called .</description></item><item><title>How does it work?</title><link>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/how-does-it-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 12:05:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/how-does-it-work/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s take a more technical overview of Punk Domains. The main Punk Domains engines are TLD Factory contracts.
TLD Factories Each factory has a TLD template that defines its business logic. Currently, there&amp;rsquo;s only one factory contract which allows for one-time TLD and domain purchases. This means that these domains never expire (holders can hold them forever).
In the future, new TLD factories will be added, each with a different business logic and each with its own mix of one-time and/or renewable TLDs/domains rules (and perhaps new business models that we haven&amp;rsquo;t thought yet about).</description></item><item><title>About Punk Domains</title><link>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 16:28:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.punk.domains/posts/about/</guid><description>Punk Domains allows you to register a domain name attached to your account address.
Why would anyone need that? Well, your crypto address is hard to remember. It starts with 0x, but then continues with 40 random characters (digits from 0 to 9 and letters from a to f).
If you want someone to send you tokens, sure you could send them your address and they could copy-paste it into their wallet.</description></item></channel></rss>